Finding Aid for Seymour Howell papers [microform], 1864-1912
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Seymour Howell papers [microform] 1864-1912
Howell, Seymour, 1841-1909.
2 microfilm reels
851482 mf 472c-mf473c
Officer with the 6th Michigan Infantry and Heavy Artillery Regiment during the Civil War; personal papers relating to wartime service and accumulated records of the 6th Michigan Heavy Artillery.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The originals of this microfilmed collection came from Howell Taylor (donor no. 2115 ) and the Washtenaw County Historical Society (donor no. 945 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The originals of the microfilmed material are located at the Bentley Historical Library.
Seymour Howell was a businessman from Saline, Michigan. During the Civil War he served as paymaster with the 6th Michigan Infantry and Heavy Artillery Regiment.
The microfilm collection of the papers of Seymour Howell have been brought together from two separate collections: papers donated by the family and records which Howell himself donated to the Washtenaw County Historical Society and which subsequently have been deposited with the Bentley Historical Library. The collection from the family includes more personal items: a diary, a wartime notebook, letters, photographs, and a scrapbook. The Howell papers from the Washtenaw County Historical Society consist almost entirely of records of the 6th Michigan Artillery maintained by Howell. These include invoices, receipts, requisitions, ordnance reports and communications, and orders.
Subjects:
Howell, Seymour, 1841-1909.; United States. Army. Michigan Artillery Regiment, 6th (1863-1865). Company F.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.
Contributors:
Howell, Charles S., d. 1903.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.
- Civil War Collection
  - Diary, letters, and other war-related materials
    (these are papers donated to the library by a Howell family member)
    - Biographical notes (Reel 1)
    - Civil War diary, 1864 (Reel 1)
    - Civil War notebook (Reel 1)
    - Correspondence, 1864-1912 (Reel 1)
    - Civil War orders, 1864-1865 (Reel 1)
    - Civil War discharge and military commissions, 1861-1865 (Reel 1)
    - Military commissions, 1891-1903 (Reel 1)
    - Receipts, 1864-1897 (Reel 1)
    - Charles S. Howell naturalization and Civil War papers (Reel 1)
    - Photographs (Reel 1)
    - Scrapbook (Reel 1)
    - Loose clippings from scrapbook (Reel 1)
    - Loose miscellanea from scrapbook (Reel 1)
  - 6th Michigan Heavy Artillery records, 1863-1866
    (These are papers accumulated by Seymour Howell and deposited with the Washtenaw County Historical Society; the files now form part of the collected historical materials of the WCHS and have been placed on deposit with the Bentley Historical Library)
    - Invoices of ordnance and ordnance stores
      - 1863-1864 (Reel 1)
      - January-March 1865 (Reel 1)
      - April-September 1865 (Reel 1)
    - Receipts for ordnance stores (Reel 1)
    - Abstracts of receipts, 1865 (Reel 1)
    - Receipts of clothes, and camp and garrison equipment, 1864-1865 (Reel 2)
    - Requisitions for ordnance stores, 1864-1865 (Reel 2)
    - Reports on the returns of clothing, camp and garrison equipage, 1864 (Reel 2)
    - Report of quarterly return of ordnance and ordnance stores, 1864-1865 (Reel 2)
    - Special field orders, 1864-1865 (Reel 2)
    - General orders of the War Dept., 1863-1865 (Reel 2)
    - Printed communications of the Ordnance Office, 1863-1864 (Reel 2)
    - Official communications of the Ordnance Office, 1864-1866 (Reel 2)
    - Papers include official correspondence, 1863-1865 (Reel 2)
    - Correspondence of Capt. Seymour Howell, 1864-1866 (Reel 2)
    - List of articles received by Seymour Howell at Fort Gaines, Ala., 1865 (Reel 2)
    - Miscellaneous lists (Reel 2)
    - Inventory of ordnance stores, 1865 (Reel 2)
    - Proceedings of board of survey at Fort Gaines, Ala., 1865 (Reel 2)
    - Abstracts of expenditures at Fort Gaines, Ala., 1863-1865 (Reel 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1860s (Reel 2)
      ( include Civil War blank forms)
Related Material
The library also has other materials from the Seymour Howell collection which were not microfilmed because they were unrelated to his wartime service. These include diaries, 1873-1904, and several artifacts from the war.